# Senior Software Engineer / Data Realizer

PROBLEM SOLVER
RESULTS-FOCUSED

SEASONED PRO

FORWARD THINKING

COLLABORATOR

VERSATILE

gregg@innovadev.net

# **PROFILE**

Twenty-three years of applying information technology experience to solve complex business problems in as simple architecture as possible. Full life-cycle experience with a range of platforms, databases, and tools to deliver business capability and visibility. Excellent communication and mentoring skills.

# **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Project / Team Leadership Ability to lead teams through successful production release cycles while maintaining positive professional developer relationships.
- Software Development Twenty-three years of developing software to meet business objectives using industry best practices and standard tools.
- **Data Management** Proven ability to distill business requirements down to appropriate data models and supporting ETL processes to meet application and reporting/analytics needs.

### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

- Database
- Data Warehousing/ETL
- Analytics

- Development
- Application Servers
- Content Management Systems

Tools: Oracle, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MarkLogic, Amazon RDS, Kimball methodology, MS DataTools, Pentaho, Talend Data Integration, Sisense, MicroStrategy, Pentaho/Saiku, Tableau, JasperServer, BIME, Java/JSF/Spring MVC/Hibernate/Acegi/Struts, Maven, JavaScript (jQuery, Angular, React), PHP, HTML5/CSS, XML, XSLT, T-SQL, PL/SQL, UML, C#, ASP, ASP.NET/ADO.NET, Visual Basic, Node, Tomcat, IIS, Adobe Experience Manager, and Wordpress.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Kuali – Senior Software Engineer

2017 to Current

- Facilitated Analytics product selection process and formal Sisense Evaluation.
- Maintained legacy ETL/Warehouse while analyzing business needs and forming forward business data strategy.

# LDS Church - Principal Software Engineer / Junior Eng. Manager

2012 to 2017

- Spearheaded Digital Asset Management strategy and architecture. Coordinated multiple department needs, architected solution, and evangelized strategy.
- Documented business processes and enterprise application maps to determine current state of portfolio.
- Designed proposals for application responsibilities, content storage and management, workflows, and messaging.
- Development lead for Event Central project which manages conference talks through the editorial process, live interpretation, translation, and publishing.
- Developed Audio Scriptures application to enable volunteer recording and approval of scriptures.
- Involved in interviewing, building teams, and aligning resources to projects. Held one-on-one reviews with engineers and mentored development team leads. Helped engineers in reaching their career goals.

### LDS Church - Senior Software Engineer / Technical Lead

2006 to 2012

Development technical lead for various projects within Supply Chain, Temple, and Other Operations portfolios including the eStore project which took the Church's distribution centers global and moved them online. This involved the creation of a store website supporting granular security model, multiple languages and currencies, multiple fulfillment centers around the world, as well as implementing an Enterprise Service Bus and integrating with backend supply chain systems. Other projects I led were: Temple Information System, Global Incident Reporting, Audio/Visual Engineering Maintenance Tracking, Church Service Missionary Tracking, and Local Unit Auditing.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Continued)

Innovadev – Owner 1999 to Current

# Recent Projects

- Salt Lake County Library Data Warehouse, ETL, Business Intelligence
- Zerorez Data migration for 50 franchises, Data Warehouse, Business Intelligence
- Blue Raven Solar Real-time Data Warehouse
- Maelle Real-time compensation engine
- Autoliv Automated testing infrastructure

### Clients

 Salt Lake County Library, Zerorez, Blue Raven Solar, Maelle, Autoliv, Microsoft Licensing, Autoliv, Iomega, First USA – PaymentTech, Jomotion.com, Informix (Found.com), TeachingMadeEasier.com, CBT Systems, Home Financial Networks, Sabin Integration, Ipinet, Wibni Consulting, LocalVoice, MachinePresence, Condie Entertainment, and John Nemeth Blues.

# **Past Employers**

Software Technology Group (STG) – Senior Software Engineer

• LDS Church	2003 to 2006
<ul> <li>Triton Investments, Inc.</li> </ul>	2003 to 2004
<ul> <li>Dollar Financial – Senior Software Engineer</li> </ul>	2002 to 2003
<ul><li>2002 Winter Olympics (SLOC) – SQL DBA/Developer</li></ul>	2001 to 2002
<ul><li>Panurgy – Web Developer</li></ul>	2000 to 2001
<ul> <li>Sprint Paranet – Web Developer / Analyst</li> </ul>	1998 to 1999
<ul> <li>Autoliv ASP, Inc. – NT Network / CAD Administrator</li> </ul>	1994 to 1998

### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

- Computer Science Studies, Weber State University
- A.A.S. Design Graphics, Weber State University
- General Education Studies, Utah State University
- Java Certified Programmer
- MCSE Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer
- MCP + Internet Microsoft Certified Professional + Internet